

Summary

I'm a builder and a maker, passionate about learning and combining different elements to create a functional unified product. In my work, I've found that JavaScript is the language that I am most passionate about and will continue to explore it as a client and server side tool. Going forward, my goal is to combine my passion for technology and science with my appreciation for aesthetics to create better web experiences.

Employment

Upstatement

Developer

Boston, MA Aug 2015 to Current

- Served as a core member of the team that built out the front end of the ValoraLife product website (https://valoralife.com/).
- As lead developer, utilized Javascript/jQuery, HTML, SCSS, PHP, and the Wordpress CMS to develop the ValoraLife blog (https://valoralife.com/blog/).
- Built out and continually maintain several internal tools using Node.js and Express.

Development Apprentice

Boston, MA May 2015 to Aug 2015

- Development apprentice at a web design agency focused on content heavy clients.
- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Documented} \ \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{addressed} \ \mathsf{bugs} \ \mathsf{on} \ \mathsf{several} \ \mathsf{projects} \ \mathsf{using} \ \mathsf{PHP}, \mathsf{JavaScript}, \mathsf{SCSS}, \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{HTML}.$
- Assisted in prototype buildout for the MIT Technology Review site redesign (https://www.technologyreview.com/).

Bonobos Guide Boston, MA May 2012 to Jun 2014

- Assisted in opening the first brick and mortar showroom for Bonobos, a men's e-commerce brand focused on supreme customer service and great fitting clothing. Bonobos continues to open new locations due to the proven success of the Boston shop.
- Sold approximately \$500,000 in merchandise over my two year tenure, while providing product guidance and styling assistance to customers.
- Point person for launch dates of new items or re-stocks, managed incoming apparel samples, fit specialist.
- Handled duties including: scheduling, event coordination, and new employee training.

ALG Interiors

Assistant

Sep 2011 to May 2012

- Assisted in executing research, planning, and design decisions for three interior decorating projects, as well as, supervised installations and photo shoots.
- Managed client invoices and purchase orders using Design Manager software, generated checks, organized sample library, and other general office work.

Dansk Investment Group. Inc.

Executive Assistant/Office Manager

Jun 2007 to May 2011

- Managed projects involving Dansk's commercial real estate portfolio including, reviewing property insurance, title insurance, leases, and the formation of new companies/entities.
- Ensured efficient general office operations for Dansk: booking travel, banking, filing, and phones.
- Worked directly with the President/CEO provided support to three other executive level managers.

Projects

Ouadrupeds

Quadrupeds pet services. An informational site for a friend's growing business. I kept it simple using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Foundation. It was really exciting to build a website that was going to help a business grow.

Hello, Boston!

For my first project in General Assembly's Web Development Immersive program I created a community website for the city of Boston. Check the weather, Instagram, and read articles with the help of APIs. I used Ruby on Rails to create a posting feature and Ajax to assist in the insertion of the comments. I had Bootstrap's help to stylize this project. Other Technologies used: PostgreSQL.

Weather

An Angular JS app using the Weather Underground API. See the forecast for today, tomorrow, or the next 5 days. This app is still being developed.

Portfolio

My revised portfolio focusing on front-end development skills. I used HTML, CSS, and jQuery to express my personality. Check out some of my technical projects, as well as, other creative projects I have contributed to.

Contact

- **■** emmagard@gmail.com
- emmagard.github.io/portfolio-Mar2015/
- **5** 781.385.9124
- **♥** Boston, MA
- **y** @e_m_m_m_a_a
- in emmagard
- n emmagard

Education

General Assembly

Web Development 2014

Otis College of Art and Design

Continuing Education Fashion/Apparel Design 2011

Simmons College

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) Arts Administration 2006

Skills

CSS3

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript

Wordpress HTML5

Git

PHP

SASS

D3 Heroku

Node.js

jQuery